Guide to the Pat Williams Papers 1979-1997
Maureen and Mike Mansfield Library, The University of Montana--Missoula
Pat Williams Papers
1979-1997
Maureen and Mike Mansfield Library Archives and Special Collections The University of Montana--Missoula Missoula, MT 59812 406-243-2053 http://www.lib.umt.edu/asc library.archives@umontana.edu
Mss 239
Williams, Pat, 1937-
87.5 linear feet
Pat Williams was in the U. S. House of Representatives for Montana from 1979 to 1997. This collection consists of the materials generated and collected by Williams' office during his eighteen years in office. Significant subjects include wilderness legislation, education, Native American issues, libraries, the National Endowments for the Arts and Humanities, labor issues, and the environment.
Biographical Note
John Patrick Williams was born in Helena on October 30, 1937. He attended Montana State University (now The University of Montana--Missoula) from 1956-1957 and received his bachelor's degree from the University of Denver in 1961. He served in the Colorado and Montana National Guards from 1961 to 1969 and taught high school in Butte from 1963 to 1969. In 1966, he was elected to the Montana State House of Representative for the 1967 session. He became executive assistant to U. S. Representative John Melcher of Montana in 1969. He maintained that position during John Melcher's first term, 1969-1971. He was a member of the Montana Governor's Employment and Training Council from 1972-1978 and a member of the Montana Reapportionment Commission for 1972-1973.
Williams was first elected to the U.S. House of Representative in 1978 and served the people of Montana in the House from 1979 to 1997. In his last two terms, 1993-1997, he represented the entire state after Montana's previous two congressional districts were combined due to national reapportionment. In 1985, he was appointed as deputy whip of the House Democratic Leadership. He chaired several committees, including the Higher Education Committee. During his tenure in the U. S. House of Representatives, Williams served on the Education, Labor, Agriculture, Natural Resources, and House Budget committees. His tenure in office is noted for his activism on behalf of education, libraries, Native American tribal sovereignty, the National Endowments for the Arts and for the Humanities, worker's concerns, wilderness protection, and environmental integrity for the future of the Western states.
Williams was especially involved in wilderness issues. During the late 1970's President Carter requested a second review of the Federally owned roadless lands throughout the United States. The Forest Service in conjunction with other Agencies completed a comprehensive Roadless Area Evaluation and Review (RARE II) and recommended that these lands be placed in timber production, multiple use or wilderness. The ultimate discussion was the responsibility of the congressional delegations of each state. Most States, having few acres of roadless land, quickly drafted, introduced and passed legislation determining the fate of the land within their borders.
By the mid 1980's Montana was one of the handful of states yet to complete the process. This lack of completion was due to the number of acres being considered and the disagreement among the legislators concerning the percentage of land to be allocated for each purpose. Early bills attempted to "release" lands to the discretion of the Forest Service as to the use. These were quickly defeated by Representatives from other States. They reasoned that such vast amounts of majestic land, in the national interest, deserved closer attention. The delegates of Montana realized that a minimum amount of wilderness would need to be associated with any successful Bill. In 1984 a Bill was agreed upon by the legislators from Montana, passing both the House and Senate, this Bill would have set aside close to 1.4 million acres of wilderness with the remainder of Montana's 6.5 million acres placed in multiple use or timber production. This Bill subsequently was vetoed by President Reagan. Congressman Pat Williams continued to introduce his version of a wilderness Bill, reflecting an equal amount of wilderness protection, until his retirement in 1996. As of 1997, Montana was the only state which has failed to resolve this issue.
After his retirement, Williams moved to Missoula, joined the Political Science faculty at The University of Montana--Missoula, and became a senior fellow at the Center for the Rocky Mountain West.
This collection consists of the materials generated and collected by Williams' office during his eighteen years in office. It includes paper, audiovisual, and three-dimensional materials. Important subjects include wilderness legislation in Montana and surrounding states, education, libraries, Native American tribal sovereignty, the National Endowments for the Arts and for the Humanities, worker's concerns, and environmental integrity in the Western United States.
The collection is divided into ten series:
Series I: General Correspondence, 21.5 linear feet and 3.5 linear feet microfiche, 1979-1996
Series II: Legislative, 22.5 linear feet, 1979-1996
Series III: Speeches and Writings, 1.5 linear feet, 1979-1996
Series IV: Press Releases, 0.5 linear feet, 1979-1987
Series V: Scheduling, 4.5 linear feet, 1979-1996
Series VI: Clippings, 14.0 linear feet, 1981-1996
Series VII: Accomplishments and Retirement, 1.0 linear foot, 1987-1996
Series VIII: Wilderness, 3.0 linear feet, 1979-1980
Series IX: Video, 10.5 linear feet; 124 items, 1979-1996
Series X: Guest Books and Student Portraits, 1.0 linear foot, 1979-1996
Series XI: Photographs, 187 items, 1979-1996
Researchers must use collection in accordance with the policies of Archives and Special Collections, the Maureen and Mike Mansfield Library, and The University of Montana--Missoula.
The collection was in the possession of Pat Williams and his staff until donation to the Archives.
The papers were donated to the K. Ross Toole Archives by the office of Pat Williams in February 1997. Additional materials, mostly those concerned with wilderness, were received from former Williams staff member Art Noonan in October 1997. Williams also donated additional audio, video and photographic materials in 2001.
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Legislators--United States
Art and state--United States; Education and state--United States; Employee rights--United States; Environmental policy--United States; Indians of North America--Government relations; Libraries and state--United States; Wilderness areas--Law and legislation--United States; United States--Politics and government-1945-1989
Montana--Politics and government--20th century; United States--Politics and government--1945-1989; United States--Politics and government--1989-
United States. Congress House; National Endowment for the Arts; University of Montana--Missoula--Alumni and alumnae; National Endowment for the Humanities
Moving images; Photographs
Montana; Moving Images; Sound Recordings; Arts and Humanities; Labor History; Environmental Conditions; Civil Procedure and Courts; Native Americans
- General Correspondence, 1979-1996; Series I; 21.5 linear feet and 3.5 linear feet microfiche
  This series consists of incoming and outgoing correspondence from Williams' office. It includes correspondence with constituents, other congressmen, and others. A great deal of the series consists of the issue-oriented form letters that were sent as responses to constituent inquiries.
  The series is subdivided into six Subseries: Form letters, form letter text, messages and invitations, personal congressional, news letter and questionnaire, and personal constituent. Form letters are arranged alphabetically by subject; form letter text, messages and invitations, personal congressional, and newsletter and questionnaire are arranged chronologically. Personal response to constituent is arranged alphabetically by name of constituent, and is on microfiche.
  - Subseries 1: Form Letters
    - Abortion, 1986-1989 (Box-folder 1/1)
    - Abortion, 1990 (Box-folder 1/2)
    - Abortion, 1991 (Box-folder 1/3)
    - Abortion, 1992 (Box-folder 1/4)
    - Acid Rain, 1986 (Box-folder 1/5)
    - Act for Better Child Care, 1988-1990 (Box-folder 1/6)
    - Adult Education, 1986 (Box-folder 1/7)
    - African Relief, 1979-1996 (Box-folder 1/8)
    - Agriculture, 1979-1989 (Box-folder 2/1)
    - Agriculture, 1990-1992 (Box-folder 2/2)
    - Agriculture, 1993-1996 (Box-folder 2/3)
    - Aluminum Plant, Bonneville, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 2/4)
    - American Heritage Trust Act, 1988-1989 (Box-folder 2/5)
    - Amtrak, 1985-1989 (Box-folder 2/6)
    - Ancient Forest Protection Act, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 2/7)
    - Apprenticeship Act, 1990 (Box-folder 2/8)
    - Appropriations, 1979-1996 (Box-folder 2/9)
    - Arctic National Wildlife Refuge, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 3/1)
    - Armed Forces, 1979-1996 (Box-folder 3/2)
    - Arms Control, undated (Box-folder 3/3)
    - Arts and Humanities, 1992-1996 (Box-folder 3/4)
    - Asbestos, 1985-1990 (Box-folder 3/5)
    - Badger Two Medicine/ANWR, 1989-1991 (Box-folder 3/6)
    - Balanced Budget, 1987-1990 (Box-folder 3/7)
    - Banking and Currency, 1985-1989 (Box-folder 3/8)
    - Banking and Currency, 1989-1994 (Box-folder 3/9)
    - Banking and Currency, 1991 (Box-folder 3/10)
    - Bases, 1989 (Box-folder 3/11)
    - Beer Tax, 1990 (Box-folder 3/12)
    - Betts Vs. Ohio, 1990 (Box-folder 3/13)
    - Biden/Gun Control, 1990 (Box-folder 3/14)
    - Blackfeet Tribe Tax, 1985 (Box-folder 3/15)
    - Bonneville Power Administration, 1986-1989 (Box-folder 3/16)
    - Judge Bork Confirmation, 1987 (Box-folder 3/17)
    - Boxing, 1988 (Box-folder 3/18)
    - Bozeman, undated (Box-folder 3/19)
    - Brady Bill, 1988-1991 (Box-folder 3/20)
    - Budget Summit, 1987-1991 (Box-folder 4/1)
    - Budget, 1990 (Box-folder 4/2)
    - Budget Resolution Update, 1986 (Box-folder 4/3)
    - Bureau of Land Management, 1989 (Box-folder 4/4)
    - Burlington Northern, 1986-1990 (Box-folder 4/5)
    - Business and Industrial, 1979-1996 (Box-folder 4/6)
    - Butte Head Start Program, 1985 (Box-folder 4/7)
    - Butte Transit System, 1985 (Box-folder 4/8)
    - Cable T.V., 1992 (Box-folder 4/9)
    - Caboose Act, 1987 (Box-folder 4/10)
    - Campaign Reform, 1983-1991 (Box-folder 4/11)
    - Campaign Reform, 1992-1996 (Box-folder 4/12)
    - Casper Weinberger, 1985 (Box-folder 4/13)
    - Charity, 1985-1990 (Box-folder 4/14)
    - Child Pornography, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 4/15)
    - Cigarette Tax, 1986-1990 (Box-folder 5/1)
    - Circle Arrow Hydro Project, undated (Box-folder 5/2)
    - Civil Rights, 1986-1989 (Box-folder 5/3)
    - Civil Rights, 1990-1993 (Box-folder 5/4)
    - Civil Rights, 1994-1996 (Box-folder 5/5)
    - Clean Air Act, 1988-1990 (Box-folder 5/6)
    - Clinton- Bill, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 5/7)
    - COLA, 1986-1989 (Box-folder 5/8)
    - COLA, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 5/9)
    - Communications, 1983-1993 (Box-folder 5/10)
    - Communications, 1994-1996 (Box-folder 5/11)
    - Community Service Block Grant, 1985-1988 (Box-folder 5/12)
    - Congressional Pay Raise, 1987-1989 (Box-folder 6/1)
    - Congressional Pay Raise, 1990 (Box-folder 6/2)
    - Contra Aide, 1986 (Box-folder 6/3)
    - Contra Aide, 1988 (Box-folder 6/4)
    - Cooperative of Rural Electrification, 1989 (Box-folder 6/5)
    - Corps of Engineers, 1991 (Box-folder 6/6)
    - Cottonwood Elementary, 1988 (Box-folder 6/7)
    - Credit Unions, 1989-1991 (Box-folder 6/8)
    - Christmas Cards, 1979-1993 (Box-folder 6/9)
    - Dairy Support Program, 1985 (Box-folder 6/10)
    - Davis Bacon Act, 1985 (Box-folder 6/11)
    - Deficit, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 6/12)
    - Democratic Study Group, Legislative Report, 1992 (Box-folder 6/13)
    - Dependant Care Tax, 1988 (Box-folder 6/14)
    - Dolphin Protection, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 6/15)
    - Drugs, 1986-1989 (Box-folder 6/16)
    - Eastern Airlines, 1988 (Box-folder 6/17)
    - Economy and Budget, 1979-1982 (Box-folder 7/1)
    - Economy and Budget, 1983-1986 (Box-folder 7/2)
    - Economy and Budget, 1987-1996 (Box-folder 7/3)
    - Education, 1979-1989 (Box-folder 7/4)
    - Education, 1990-1996 (Box-folder 7/5)
    - El Salvador, 1985-1987 (Box-folder 7/6)
    - Elkhorn Wilderness, 1988 (Box-folder 7/7)
    - Energy, 1979-1985 (Box-folder 8/1)
    - Energy, 1991-1996 (Box-folder 8/2)
    - English Language, 1987-1996 (Box-folder 8/3)
    - Environment, 1979-1983 (Box-folder 8/4)
    - Environment, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 8/5)
    - Environment, 1986-1991 (Box-folder 8/6)
    - Environment, 1992 (Box-folder 8/7)
    - Environment, 1992 (Box-folder 9/1)
    - Environment, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 9/2)
    - Environment, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 9/3)
    - Equal Rights Amendment, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 9/4)
    - Extension Service, 1986 (Box-folder 9/5)
    - Family Medical Leave Act, 1988-1992 (Box-folder 9/6)
    - Farm Bill, 1985-1987 (Box-folder 9/7)
    - Farm Bill, 1990 (Box-folder 9/8)
    - FBI Retirement, 1986 (Box-folder 9/9)
    - Federal Deficit, 1985-1987 (Box-folder 10/1)
    - Federal Employees, 1983-1989 (Box-folder 10/2)
    - Federal Employees, 1990-1996 (Box-folder 10/3)
    - Federal Reserve System, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 10/4)
    - Fetal Tissue Research, 1992 (Box-folder 10/5)
    - Financial Integrity Act, 1990 (Box-folder 10/6)
    - Keep the Flag Flying, 1989-1994 (Box-folder 10/7)
    - Flathead Irrigation, undated (Box-folder 10/8)
    - Fluoride in Drinking Water, 1986 (Box-folder 10/9)
    - Foreign Affairs, 1983-1996 (Box-folder 10/10)
    - Forest Service, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 10/11)
    - Garcia Decision, 1985 (Box-folder 10/12)
    - Gas Tax, 1988-1990 (Box-folder 10/13)
    - Gay Bill of Rights, 1985-1990 (Box-folder 10/14)
    - General Revenue Sharing, 1985 (Box-folder 10/15)
    - Germ Warfare Experiments, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 10/16)
    - Germ Warfare, Japanese Biochemical Warfare during WWII, 1950-1996 (Box-folder 10/17)
    - Global Warming, undated (Box-folder 10/18)
    - Government Spending, 1992 (Box-folder 10/19)
    - Grace Commission, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 11/1)
    - Grazing, 1985-1992 (Box-folder 11/2)
    - Grizzly Bear Introduction, 1988 (Box-folder 11/3)
    - Gulf War, 1990 (Box-folder 11/4)
    - Gun Control, 1985-1990 (Box-folder 11/5)
    - Gun Control, 1991 (Box-folder 11/6)
    - Gun Control, 1992-1996 (Box-folder 12/1)
    - Gwen Tower, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 12/2)
    - Head Start, 1986-1990 (Box-folder 12/3)
    - Health Care, 1983-1986 (Box-folder 12/4)
    - Health Care, 1987 (Box-folder 12/5)
    - Health Care, 1988 (Box-folder 12/6)
    - Health Care, 1989 (Box-folder 12/7)
    - Health Care, 1990 (Box-folder 12/8)
    - Health Care, 1991-1993 (Box-folder 12/9)
    - Health Care, 1994 (Box-folder 13/1)
    - Health Care, 1994 (Box-folder 13/2)
    - Health Care, 1995 (Box-folder 13/3)
    - Health Care, 1996 (Box-folder 13/4)
    - Helmet Law, 1991 (Box-folder 13/5)
    - Honduras, 1988 (Box-folder 13/6)
    - Honey, 1985 (Box-folder 13/7)
    - Housing, 1985-1995 (Box-folder 13/8)
    - Impact Aide, 1987 (Box-folder 13/9)
    - Impact Aide, 1985-1991 (Box-folder 13/10)
    - Immigration, 1987-1996 (Box-folder 13/11)
    - Insurance, 1985-1992 (Box-folder 14/1)
    - Invent America, 1990 (Box-folder 14/2)
    - International Family Planning, 1990 (Box-folder 14/3)
    - Individual Retirement Accounts, 1990 (Box-folder 14/4)
    - Ireland Human Rights Violations, 1992 (Box-folder 14/5)
    - Japanese Warrior Memorial, 1988 (Box-folder 14/6)
    - Job Corps, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 14/7)
    - Johnson O'Malley, 1985-1990 (Box-folder 14/8)
    - Justice and Judiciary, 1991-1993 (Box-folder 14/9)
    - Justice and Judiciary, 1994-1996 (Box-folder 14/10)
    - Kangaroo, 1986 (Box-folder 14/11)
    - Labor Appropriations, 1990-1992 (Box-folder 14/12)
    - Labor, 1983-1989 (Box-folder 14/13)
    - Labor, 1990-1993 (Box-folder 15/1)
    - Labor, 1994-1996 (Box-folder 15/2)
    - Lake Koocanoosa, 1988 (Box-folder 15/3)
    - Landfill Regulation, 1988-1989 (Box-folder 15/4)
    - Lead Pollution Prevention, 1988-1990 (Box-folder 15/5)
    - Lease Purchase Industry, 1990 (Box-folder 15/6)
    - Lewis and Clark Interpretive Center, 1987-1990 (Box-folder 15/7)
    - Lewistown Insurance, 1991 (Box-folder 15/8)
    - Libya, 1986 (Box-folder 15/9)
    - Line Item Veto, 1985-1989 (Box-folder 15/10)
    - Low Income Americans, 1988-1989 (Box-folder 15/11)
    - Low Income Energy Assistance, 1988-1991 (Box-folder 15/12)
    - Lump Sum Retirement Benefits, 1990 (Box-folder 15/13)
    - Magnet School Program, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 15/14)
    - Meat Inspection, 1990 (Box-folder 15/15)
    - Medicare, 1985-1990 (Box-folder 16/1)
    - Milage Tax, 1985 (Box-folder 16/2)
    - Military Mail, 1991 (Box-folder 16/3)
    - Minimum Wage, 1988-1989 (Box-folder 16/4)
    - Mining, 1988-1991 (Box-folder 16/5)
    - Mining, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 16/6)
    - Montana Congratulation, 1992 (Box-folder 16/7)
    - Montana Distinguished Service, 1986 (Box-folder 16/8)
    - Montana Power Company, 1984 (Box-folder 16/9)
    - Montana Rail-Link, 1987 (Box-folder 16/10)
    - Montana Unemployment, 1988 (Box-folder 16/11)
    - Moratorium on Bank Activities, 1988 (Box-folder 16/12)
    - Morgan Custody Case, 1989 (Box-folder 16/13)
    - MX Missile, 1985-1989 (Box-folder 16/14)
    - National Defense, 1983-1995 (Box-folder 16/15)
    - National Endowment for the Arts, 1990 (Box-folder 16/16)
    - National Food Service Week, 1989 (Box-folder 16/17)
    - National Guard, 1987-1989 (Box-folder 16/18)
    - National Institutes of Health, 1990 (Box-folder 16/19)
    - National Parks Overflight, 1986 (Box-folder 16/20)
    - National Weather Service, 1994 (Box-folder 16/21)
    - Native American Issues, 1986-1995 (Box-folder 17/1)
    - Nicaragua, 1985 (Box-folder 17/2)
    - Northern Tier, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 17/3)
    - Notch, 1985-1990 (Box-folder 17/4)
    - Office Administration, 1981-1996 (Box-folder 17/5)
    - Oil, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 17/6)
    - Older American Freedom of Work, 1990 (Box-folder 17/7)
    - Ollie North, 1987 (Box-folder 17/8)
    - Persian Gulf War, 1987 (Box-folder 17/9)
    - Pinesdale Investigation, 1990 (Box-folder 17/10)
    - Polygraph, 1988 (Box-folder 17/11)
    - Pornography, 1986-1988 (Box-folder 17/12)
    - Postal Service, 1985-1991 (Box-folder 17/13)
    - Prayer, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 17/14)
    - Program Trading, 1990 (Box-folder 17/15)
    - Public Pension Equity Restoration, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 17/16)
    - Public Service Research Council, 1987 (Box-folder 18/1)
    - Pyramid Lumber, 1989 (Box-folder 18/2)
    - Quackery Act, 1985 (Box-folder 18/3)
    - Racketeer and Organization Act, 1990 (Box-folder 18/4)
    - Radio Fees, 1989 (Box-folder 18/5)
    - Railroad Retirement, 1985-1993 (Box-folder 18/6)
    - Jeanette Rankin, 1985-1988 (Box-folder 18/7)
    - Real Property Regulation, 1987 (Box-folder 18/8)
    - Religious Freedom Restoration Act, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 18/9)
    - Replacement Workers, 1988 (Box-folder 18/10)
    - Reproductive Health Equity Act, 1988 (Box-folder 18/11)
    - Research Freedom Act, 1990 (Box-folder 18/12)
    - Rocky Boys Reservation, 1989 (Box-folder 18/13)
    - Rural Electrification Administration, 1985-1991 (Box-folder 18/14)
    - Rural Health Care, 1989-1992 (Box-folder 18/15)
    - Salish/Kootenai Game Regulations, 1989 (Box-folder 18/16)
    - Satellite Dishes, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 18/17)
    - Savings and Loan, 1988-1990 (Box-folder 18/18)
    - Social Services, 1979-1981 (Box-folder 18/19)
    - Social Services, 1982 (Box-folder 19/1)
    - Social Services, 1983 (Box-folder 19/2)
    - Social Services, 1984-1986 (Box-folder 19/3)
    - Social Services, 1987-1989 (Box-folder 19/4)
    - Social Services, 1990-1992 (Box-folder 19/5)
    - Soil Conservation, 1985 (Box-folder 19/6)
    - Small Business, 1985 (Box-folder 20/1)
    - Stafford Loans, 1989 (Box-folder 20/2)
    - Strikers Rights, 1990 (Box-folder 20/3)
    - Strategic Defense, 1985 (Box-folder 20/4)
    - Student Requests, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 20/5)
    - Sunshine Mining, 1988-1990 (Box-folder 20/6)
    - Taft Institute, 1990 (Box-folder 20/7)
    - Tax Issues, 1981-1984 (Box-folder 20/8)
    - Tax Issues, 1985 (Box-folder 20/9)
    - Tax Issues, 1985 (Box-folder 20/10)
    - Tax Issues, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 20/11)
    - Tax Issues, 1988 (Box-folder 20/12)
    - Tax Issues, 1989 (Box-folder 21/1)
    - Tax Issues, 1990 (Box-folder 21/2)
    - Tax Issues, 1990 (Box-folder 21/3)
    - Tax Issues, 1991-1993 (Box-folder 21/4)
    - Tax Issues, 1994-1996 (Box-folder 21/5)
    - Teachers Issues, 1990 (Box-folder 21/6)
    - Teen Pregnancy, 1986 (Box-folder 21/7)
    - Telecommunications Act, 1989 (Box-folder 21/8)
    - Term Limits, 1990 (Box-folder 21/9)
    - Texas Air Corporation, 1988 (Box-folder 21/10)
    - Timber Issues, 1987-1991 (Box-folder 22/1)
    - Transportation, 1980-1982 (Box-folder 22/2)
    - Transportation, 1983-1987 (Box-folder 22/3)
    - Transportation, 1988-1991 (Box-folder 22/4)
    - Transportation, 1992 (Box-folder 22/5)
    - Transportation, 1993-1996 (Box-folder 22/6)
    - Tribal Issues, 1985-1991 (Box-folder 23/1)
    - Trade Issues, 1985-1993 (Box-folder 23/2)
    - TRIO Programs, 1985 and 1997 (Box-folder 23/3)
    - Urban Indian Health, 1985-1988 (Box-folder 23/4)
    - United Nations, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 23/5)
    - Veal Protection Act, 1987 (Box-folder 23/6)
    - Veterans Issues, 1980-1989 (Box-folder 23/7)
    - Veterans Issues, 1990-1996 (Box-folder 23/8)
    - Vietnam Women's Memorial, 1988 (Box-folder 23/9)
    - Virginia City, 1990 (Box-folder 23/10)
    - Visually Impaired Program, 1988 (Box-folder 23/11)
    - Vitamin Regulations, 1992 (Box-folder 23/12)
    - Vocational Education, 1989 (Box-folder 23/13)
    - Voter Registration, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 23/14)
    - Voucher Proposal, 1986 (Box-folder 23/15)
    - Water Resources, 1987-1990 (Box-folder 24/1)
    - WIC, 1987 (Box-folder 24/2)
    - Wilderness, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 24/3)
    - Wilderness, 1986 (Box-folder 24/4)
    - Wilderness, 1987 (Box-folder 24/5)
    - Wilderness, 1987 (Box-folder 24/6)
    - Wilderness, 1987 (Box-folder 24/7)
    - Wilderness, 1988 (Box-folder 24/8)
    - Wilderness, 1989 (Box-folder 24/9)
    - Wilderness, 1990 (Box-folder 25/1)
    - Wilderness, 1991-1992 (Box-folder 25/2)
    - Wolf Recovery, 1989-1991 (Box-folder 25/3)
    - Wool Act, 1985-1990 (Box-folder 25/4)
    - Women In Development Act, 1988-1989 (Box-folder 25/5)
    - Women In Farm Economics, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 25/6)
  - Subseries 2: Form Letter Text
    - Form Letter Text, 1979 (Box-folder 26/1)
    - Form Letter Text, 1980-1984 (Box-folder 26/2)
    - Form Letter Text, 1980-1984 (Box-folder 26/3)
    - Form Letter Text, 1980-1984 (Box-folder 26/4)
    - Form Letter Text, 1980-1984 (Box-folder 26/5)
    - Form Letter Text, 1980-1984 (Box-folder 26/6)
    - Form Letter Text, 1980-1984 (Box-folder 26/7)
    - Form Letter Text, 1980-1984 (Box-folder 26/8)
    - Form Letter Text, 1980-1984 (Box-folder 27/1)
    - Form Letter Text, 1980-1984 (Box-folder 27/2)
    - Form Letter Text, 1980-1984 (Box-folder 27/3)
    - Form Letter Text, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 27/4)
    - Form Letter Text, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 27/5)
    - Form Letter Text, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 27/6)
    - Form Letter Text, 1987 (Box-folder 28/1)
    - Form Letter Text, 1987 (Box-folder 28/2)
    - Form Letter Text, 1987 (Box-folder 28/3)
    - Form Letter Text, 1987 (Box-folder 28/4)
    - Form Letter Text, 1988 (Box-folder 28/5)
    - Form Letter Text, 1988 (Box-folder 28/6)
    - Form Letter Text, 1988 (Box-folder 28/7)